{"tossups": [{"question": "One leader at this battle changed his mind in the middle of a counterattack when a nobleman asked \u201cwould you go upon your death?\u201d The Earl of Carnwath was partly blamed for losing this battle, which helped bring about a surrender at Truro. The victorious side at this battle, which was fought in Northamptonshire, took damage on its left wing under the command of Henry Ireton, who faced an assault by Prince Rupert. For the point, name this decisive June 1645 victory for Oliver Cromwell.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Naseby</u></b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This city, the ruins of which are today found within Khoms, was guarded by the Third Augustan Legion against Berber raids. After siding against the victorious Julius Caesar in a civil war, three million pounds of this city\u2019s chief export, olive oil, were annually sent to Caesar. This city was used as a trading hub in Africa due to its position at the mouth of the Wadi Lebda but was abandoned after a Muslim invasion circa 647 A.D. For the point, name this former Carthaginian city found in present-day Libya.", "answer": "<b><u>Leptis Magna</u></b> (accept <b><u>LPQ</u></b>Y; or <b><u>Lepcis Magna</u></b>; or <b><u>L\u00e9ptis Meg\u00e1l\u0113</u></b>; or <b><u>Neapolis</u></b>; or <b><u>Leptimagnese</u></b> City; or <b><u>Ulpia Traiana</u></b>; or <b><u>Lepti Maggiore</u></b>; or <b><u>Labdah</u></b>; prompt on \"Leptis\")", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "These vessels were sometimes called <em>La Nao de la China</em> due to the predominantly Chinese goods that they carried. Arturo Giraldez wrote a book about these vessels partly subtitled \u201cthe Dawn of the Global Economy.\u201d The Cavite [[kah-VEE-tay]] shipyard was used to build these vessels, which often relied on a route named for a man who served under Miguel de Legazpi [[leh-GAHZ-pee]]. Silver was often collected from Acapulco by these vessels, which brought luxury items to the New World. For the point, name these vessels that departed from the Spanish Philippines.", "answer": "<b><u>Manila Galleon</u></b>s (accept <b><u>Gale\u00f3n de Manila</u></b>; accept <b><u>Galyon ng Maynila</u></b>; accept <em>The Age of Trade: The</em> <em><b><u>Manila Galleon</u></b>s and the Dawn of the Global Economy</em>; do not accept or prompt on \"Spanish Treasure Fleet\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "School of the Americas graduate Franck Romain, a leader of this group, planned the St. Jean [[JOHN]] Bosco massacre in a failed attempt to kill future president Jean-Bertrand Aristide. This organization sold corpses to the U.S. medical establishment for three dollars a head while led by Luckner Cambronne, known as the \"Vampire of the Caribbean.\" Formerly known as the \"Hooded Men,\" this paramilitary's leaders often doubled as <em>vodou</em> priests who wielded machetes and wore straw hats. The regime of \"Papa Doc\" Duvalier was supported by, for the point, what militia from Haiti?", "answer": "Tonton <b><u>Macoute</u></b> (accept The <b><u>Macoute</u></b>; accept <b><u>Volontaires de la S\u00e9curit\u00e9</u></b> <b><u>Nationale</u></b> or <b><u>Volunteers of National Security</u></b>; accept <b><u>VSN</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In 2021, one work by this man sold for $7, only to be re-sold for $260,000 three days later. This graphic designer who specializes in non-fungible tokens produced his $66,666.66 \u201cCrossroads\u201d based on the 2020 presidential election. This man\u2019s NFT of \"Everydays - The First 5000 Days\" was auctioned by Christie\u2019s for $69 million. For the point, name this Super Bowl artist whose other works include \u201cFix Kanye\u201d and \u201cFeed the Beast,\u201d and whose name comes from a 1980\u2019s plush toy.", "answer": "<b><u>Beeple</u></b> (or Michael Joseph \"Mike\" <b><u>Winklemann</u></b>; accept <b><u>Beeple</u></b> Crap)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "One reason for this conflict was the perception by one side that the central government betrayed the principle of <em>sonno joi</em>. After the <em>Seikanron</em> [[say-KAHN-rohn]] debate, a leader of one side in this conflict created a secessionist movement in his namesake province. The siege of Kumamoto Castle and the Battle of Tabaruzaka took place during this conflict. At this conflict's final Battle of Shiroyama, Saigo Takamori was shot and fatally wounded. For the point, name this uprising of disaffected samurai against the Meiji Emperor in 1877.", "answer": "<b><u>Satsuma</u></b> Rebellion (or <b><u>Seinan</u></b> War; accept <b><u>Seinan</u></b> Senso)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In response to a threat, this man once replied, \"The thicker the hay, the easier mowed!\" An attack by Sarus, a member of the rival Amal family, prompted one campaign by this man, who was succeeded by his brother-in-law Athaulf. Priscus Attalus was declared emperor by this man after Honorius failed to give him command of the army. His presence at the Battle of Frigidus helped Theodosius defeat the Franks, but his lack of recognition prompted him to carry out a 410 sack of Rome. For the point, name this first and most powerful king of the Visigoths.", "answer": "<b><u>Alaric</u></b> I (accept <b><u>Alrik</u></b>; accept <b><u>Alaric</u></b>us)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This dynasty came to power with the assistance of the French priest Pigneau de Behaine [[peen-YOH duh buh-HEHN]]. This dynasty's first ruler was given refuge by King Ang Eng after escaping the Tay Son. Prior to protests by its first emperor Gia Long, the Jiaqing [[JYAH-CHING]] emperor rejected this dynasty's proposal to call its land \"Nam Viet.\" This dynasty's capital was located at Ph\u00fa Xu\u00e2n [[FOO SOO-ahn]], which is now known as Hu\u1ebf [[HWEH]]. For the point, name this last Vietnamese dynasty, which shares its name with the most common Vietnamese surname.", "answer": "<b><u>Nguyen</u></b> [[WIN]] Dynasty (prompt on \"Vietnam\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "During this conflict, bombers from the <em>Victorious</em> and <em>Furious</em> attacked merchant vessels during the Raid on Kirkenes. An advance through Salla was the objective of the XXXVI [36th] Mountain Corps' in a portion of this conflict's Operation Silver Fox. After serving as prime minister during an earlier conflict, Risto Ryti served as president during this conflict, in which one side aimed to annex East Karelia. Fought fifteen months after the Winter War, for the point, what conflict was fought as part of World War Two between the Soviet Union and Finland?", "answer": "<b><u>Continuation</u></b> War (accept <b><u>Finnish</u></b> Front of the <b><u>Great Patriotic War</u></b>; accept Second <b><u>Soviet-Finnish war</u></b>; prompt on \"World War II\"; prompt on \"Great Patriotic War\"; prompt on \"Soviet-Finnish War\"; do not prompt or accept \"Winter War\" or \"First Soviet-Finnish War\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This man was punched by Cleve Bailey for introducing a rider prohibiting Federal funds to be given to institutions that refused to desegregate after <em>Brown v. Board</em>. The Qualifications of Members Clause was tested in a Supreme Court case brought by this man against John McCormack, which found this man\u2019s exclusion from the House unconstitutional. This Congressman, who was nicknamed \"Mr. Civil Rights,\" was succeeded by Charlie Rangel in a post he held from 1945 to 1971. For the point, name this first African-American representative elected from New York.", "answer": "Adam Clayton <b><u>Powell</u></b> Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "During this dynasty, the philosopher Zhu Xi [[ZHOO SHEE]] formulated the philosophy of the \"investigation of things.\" This dynasty rose to power after the Five Dynasties and Ten Kingdoms Period. This dynasty's Southern period began after it lost control of northern China to the Jurchen Jin Dynasty, moving its capital from Kaifeng to modern-day Hangzhou [[HAWNG-CHO]]. This dynasty fell after it was defeated at the Battle of Yamen by Zhang Hongfan's Mongol troops. For the point, name this Chinese dynasty that was conquered by the Yuan dynasty.", "answer": "<b><u>Song</u></b> Dynasty (accept Southern or Northern <b><u>Song</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "At a 1962 New York Philharmonic performance of a work in this genre, Leonard Bernstein told the audience he disagreed with Glenn Gould\u2019s interpretation of it. An A minor piece in this genre was premiered by its composer\u2019s wife, Clara Schumann. Sergei Rachmaninoff dedicated the second of his four works in this genre to his hypnotherapist. Beethoven\u2019s fifth and final work in this genre is nicknamed \u201cEmperor.\" For the point, name this genre of works for a keyboard soloist and orchestra.", "answer": "<b><u>Piano Concerto</u></b> (prompt on \u201cConcerto\u201d)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Sites like Siddens Valley and Clevesy Pass were named after soldiers who fought in this battle. A Seventh-Day Adventist named Paul Nobuo Tatsuguchi served as a surgeon during this battle, as recollected in an extensive diary. Yasuyo Yamasaki was killed at this battle, which prompted an evacuation from Kiska. Codenamed Operation Landcrab, this was the only land battle of World War Two that occurred in North America. Fought under snowy conditions, for the point, what battle of the Aleutian Islands Campaign was fought in Alaska?", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Attu</u></b> (accept Operation <b><u>Landcrab</u></b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Due to the outcome of this battle being obscured by dust, one general ordered his soldier Pindarus to kill him. That man was declared the \"Last of the Romans\" by his brother-in-law and fellow general at this battle, which occurred in a narrow pass in the province of Macedonia. This final battle of the Wars of the Second Triumvirate led to the eastern provinces of the Roman Empire being given to a former general of Julius Caesar. For the point, name this defeat of the Liberator Army, led by Brutus and Cassius, by Mark Antony and Octavian in 42 BC.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Philippi</u></b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This U.S. case was cited as a primary example in the first major case overseen by the High Court of Australia, <em>D'Emden v. Pedder</em>. In this case, one state\u2019s attempt to tax a federal holding violated the Supremacy Clause, according to John Marshall. The representative of the namesake Mid-Atlantic state in this case, which sought to impose a tax on a federal institution, argued that the \u201cConstitution is silent on the subject of banks.\" For the point, name this 1819 case argued by Daniel Webster, who represented the Second Bank of the U.S.", "answer": "<em><b><u>McCulloch</u></b> v. Maryland</em> (or <em>James</em> <em><b><u>McCulloch</u></b> v. The State of Maryland, John James</em>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A sub-group of these people named the Hohokam built the largest canal system in North America to provide water to settlements like Snaketown. Athabaskan migratory people such as the Navajo and Apache called these people the \"Ancient Enemies\" due to frequent clashes for land and resources. These people, whose name comes from the Spanish for \"village,\" built adobe brick homes at sites in Chaco Canyon. For the point, name this Native American culture of the American Southwest including the Zuni and Hopi, once known as the Anasazi.", "answer": "Ancestral <b><u>Pueblo</u></b>an Culture (accept <b><u>Pueblo</u></b>ans or <b><u>Pueblo</u></b> people; accept <b><u>Anasazi</u></b> before mentioned; accept <b><u>Hisatsinom</u></b>)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "This leader composed the Hino da Carta and Hino da Independencia. This man faced the \"Night of the Broken Bottles,\" after which he abdicated his throne. This \"Soldier King\" crushed the \"Confederation of the Equator\" before fighting a southern neighbor in the Cisplatine War. This man declared independence from his father, though he returned later to lead a \"Liberal War\" in Portugal. Crowned in Rio de Janeiro, for the point, who was this first Emperor of Brazil?", "answer": "Dom <b><u>Pedro I</u></b> (accept King Dom <b><u>Pedro IV</u></b> of Portugal; accept <b><u>Pedro the</u></b> <b><u>Liberator</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Minor players in this phenomenon included the Dave Clark Five and Herman\u2019s Hermits. DJ Murray the K played a key role in this sensation, often referring to himself as \u201cthe 5th\u201d member of a certain band. A February 1964 appearance on the Ed Sullivan Show is cited as beginning this event. The song \u201cI Want to Hold Your Hand\u201d helped launch, for the point, what phenomenon, which saw UK bands like the Rolling Stones, The Who, and The Beatles all achieve popular success in the United States?", "answer": "The <b><u>British Invasion</u></b> (prompt on answers involving the various bands coming to the United States from <b><u>Britain</u></b>; prompt on answers such as \"Rock and Roll\")", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "Operation Green was abandoned after the signing of this agreement, which was the subject of P. E. Caquet\u2019s book <em>The Bell of Treason</em>. \u00c9douard Daladier [[dah-lah-DYEH]] represented France in this agreement, which brought about \u201cpeace in our time\u201d according to one signatory. This agreement resulted in the cession of the Sudetenland as part of a policy of appeasement. For the point, name this treaty that Adolf Hitler signed with Neville Chamberlain and other western powers to annex a portion of Czechoslovakia.", "answer": "<b><u>Munich</u></b> Agreement (accept <b><u>Munich</u></b> Pact; accept <b><u>Mn\u00edchovsk\u00e1</u></b> dohoda; accept <b><u>M\u00fcnchner</u></b> Abkommen; accept <b><u>Munich Betrayal</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Using this ancient man's descriptions, archaeologist Ehud Netzer discovered the location of Herod's Tomb near Herodium. While under siege at Yodfat, this man had a divine revelation about the rise of the Flavians which led to his pardoning and allotment of an imperial pension. Beginning with the Maccabean revolt and ending at Masada, this writer recounts the rise and downfall of his people in <em>De Bello Judaico</em>. For the point, name this Jewish Roman chronicler and companion of Emperor Titus who provides extra-biblical accounts of men like John the Baptist and Jesus of Nazareth.", "answer": "Titus Flavius <b><u>Josephus</u></b> (or <b><u>Yosef</u></b> ben Matityahu)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "In a statement of resistance to this act, William Bradford added a skull and crossbones to the top of the Pennsylvania Journal. After an impassioned speech by William Pitt, this act was repealed under Lord Rockingham. A Congress named for this act held in New York passed the \u201cDeclaration of Rights and Grievances\u201d which in part called for the end of taxation without representation. For the point, name this 1765 Act, an attempt to pay for the defense of the American colonies by taxing paper products.", "answer": "<b><u>Stamp</u></b> Act of 1765 (accept <b><u>Duties in American Colonies</u></b> Act 1765)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Pavel Schilling improved upon a version of this non-medical technology developed by Samuel Thomas von S\u00f6mmerring. Wilhelm Weber [[VEH-buh]] worked with a mathematician who created his own commutator to improve this technology, which made use of a register developed by Alfred Vail. A needle-based technology of this type was developed by Charles Wheatstone. Induction impulses improved the throughput of this technology, a version of which was patented by Samuel Morse. For the point, name this electric communication technology.", "answer": "<b><u>Telegraph</u></b>y (accept <b><u>Telegram</u></b>)", "metadata": "Science - Physics"}, {"question": "The perpetrators of this event were targeted by the Disqualification Act, which forbade them from holding public office. James Bowdoin [[BOU-dun]] declared martial law during this event and authorized direct reimbursements to Benjamin Lincoln. During this event, one side was unable to raid a courthouse due to the defense of William Shepherd, forcing them to retreat to Springfield Armory. For the point, name this 1786 Massachusetts rebellion, led by a veteran of the Revolutionary War, which exposed the weaknesses of the Articles of Confederation.", "answer": "<b><u>Shays'</u></b> Rebellion", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Alistair Horne\u2019s book <em>The Price of Glory</em> focuses on this battle, in which control of Fleury [[FLURRY]] changed sixteen times. Fort Souville was repeatedly attacked during this battle, in which one general\u2019s Order of the Day famously ended with the words \u201cthey shall not pass.\u201d Fort Douamont was captured by Robert Nivelle at this battle, where artillery was transported day and night along a road called the \u201cSacred Way.\" Erich von Falkenhayn [[FAHL-ken-hine]] was defeated at this ten-month battle. For the point, name this 1916 World War One battle in France, the longest of the war.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Verdun</u></b> (accept Bataille de <b><u>Verdun</u></b>; Schlacht um <b><u>Verdun</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This empire won the battle of al-Harra and the Battle of Marj Rahit, causing centuries of war between the Qays and Yaman tribes. A ruler of this empire introduced the dinar as a currency, based on the Roman denarius. Abd Allah ibn al-Zubayr opposed this empire, as did the General Abu Muslim. Abd al-Malik led this empire, founding the Dome of the Rock in Jerusalem. Caliphs like Yazid and Marwin ruled this empire after it was founded by Muawiyah I, a brother in law of Muhammad. For the point, name this Caliphate preceding the Abbasids.", "answer": "<b><u>Umayyad</u></b> Caliphate (or al-Khil\u0101fah al-<b><u>\u02beUmaw\u012byah</u></b>; accept <b><u>Umayyad</u></b>s; accept \"Empire\" in place of \"Caliphate\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Charles Edward Stuart once fled to this island while dressed as Flora MacDonald's maid. This island's Rubha an D\u00f9nain peninsula is home to the so-called \"Viking Canal.\" According to legend, this island was where Sc\u00e1thach [[SKAH-hak]] trained C\u00fa Chulainn [[koo-KUL-in]]. In 1830, Hugh MacAskill founded this island's most famous distillery and named it for the local Talisker estate. This island's capital and largest city is Portree. For the point, name this Scottish island, the largest of the Inner Hebrides.", "answer": "Isle of <b><u>Skye</u></b> (or Isle o <b><u>Skye</u></b>; accept An t-Eilean <b><u>Sgitheanach</u></b>; accept ilean a' <b><u>Che\u00f2</u></b>)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "This person worked with Kato Shidzue six years after she accused Kato of murder, and she may have fabricated the story of Sadie Sach's death. This scholar rescued Olive Byrne, the inspiration for Wonder Woman. This woman worked with her sister, the hunger striker Ethel Byrne, and she was prosecuted under the Comstock Act for writing <em>Family</em> <em>Limitation</em>. Authoring \"What Every Mother Should Know,\" for the point, what birth control activist created an organization that evolved into Planned Parenthood?", "answer": "Margaret <b><u>Sanger</u></b> (or Margaret Higgins <b><u>Sanger</u></b>; or Margaret Louise <b><u>Higgins</u></b>; or Margaret <b><u>Sanger</u></b> Slee)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This event is the latter of two conflicts highlighted in Diane Gilliam Fisher's poetry collection <em>Kettle Bottom</em>. Members of one side during this conflict travelled aboard a train renamed the Blue Steel Special. Bill Blizzard led one side during this conflict that was opposed by a 2,000-man force assembled by Sheriff Don Chafin in Logan County. Martin bombers controversially attacked strikers during this 1921 event involving the United Mine Workers. Preceded by the Matewan Massacre in the same state, for the point, what was this labor uprising in West Virginia, the largest in U.S. history?", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Blair Mountain</u></b> (prompt on \"Coal Wars\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Diplomat Megasthenes [[meh-GAS-thuh-nees]] claimed a tribe living in this empire, the <em>Surasena</em>, worshipped Heracles as their founder. A ruler of this empire gave Seleucus I Nicator [[seh-LOO-kus \"the first\" neh-KAY-tor]] elephants he used at the Battle of Ipsus as a part of a marriage alliance between the two. This empire fought a bloody war against the king-less Kalinga people, which convinced one of this state's rulers to convert to Buddhism. For the point, name this Indian empire with capital at Pataliputra, ruled by Ashoka.", "answer": "<b><u>Maurya</u></b>n Empire (accept <b><u>Maurya</u></b>ns)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "William Proxmire was sworn in during the middle of this event, which led to $6,000 in printing fees being spent to enter what was said into the <em>Congressional Record</em>. A 1957 Civil Rights Act was accused of being \u201ccruel and unusual\u201d during this event, which broke Wayne Morse's previous record. Lasting for 24 hours and 18 minutes, this event was carried out by a Dixiecrat. For the point, name this longest attempt to \u201ctalk out a bill\u201d in Senate history, completed by a South Carolina segregationist.", "answer": "Strom <b><u>Thurmond</u></b>'s <b><u>filibuster</u></b> of the 1957 Civil Rights Act (accept equivalents such as the <b><u>Filibuster</u></b> of Strom <b><u>Thurmond</u></b> of the Civil Rights Act of 1957)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Preliminary actions to this battle included the failure of Operation Ten-Go, which resulted in the sinking of the <em>Yamato</em>. This battle's land portion began with a landing at Hagushi beach and the capture of the Kadena and Yomitan airbases. Codenamed Operation Iceberg, this battle has been referred to as the \u201ctyphoon of steel\u201d due to the volume of <em>kamikaze</em> attacks and its overall ferocity. Including the largest amphibious assault in the Pacific theatre of World War Two, for the point, what is this battle which started immediately after the Battle of Iwo Jima in March 1945?", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Okinawa</u></b> (accept <b><u>Operation Iceberg</u></b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "With Mairead Maguire, this woman organized a group of 10,000 women with linked arms to protest at the DMZ, calling for a formal end to the Korean War. This woman describes the Cold War-era CIA as \"liberal, nonviolent and honorable\" in her autobiography <em>My Life on the Road</em>. This honorary co-chair of 2017 Women's March once said \u201ca woman needs a man like a fish needs a bicycle.\u201d For the point, name this Second-wave feminist and editor of the magazine <em>Ms.</em> [[miz]].", "answer": "Gloria <b><u>Steinem</u></b> (or Gloria Marie <b><u>Steinem</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The San Carlos Reservoir was created when the U.S. government dammed this river by building the Coolidge Dam near the city of Globe. Prior to the Gadsden Purchase, this river served as the boundary between the U.S. and Mexico in modern-day Arizona. This tributary, whose mouth is near the city of Yuma, is known as \"Akimel\" in the Pima tongue. For the point, name this tributary of the Colorado River which names a species of lizard known as its namesake \"Monster.\"", "answer": "<b><u>Gila</u></b> [[HEE-lah]] River (accept Keli <b><u>Akimel</u></b> before mentioned; accept <b><u>Haa Si'il</u></b>)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "A Byzantine theologian with this name was the first to propose the essence/energy distinction and famously defended Hesychasm. One pope with this name gave the <em>Liber</em> <em>extra</em> decrees and founded the Papal Inquisition. The Cappadocian Fathers included two men of this name from Nazianzus and Nyssa. Henry IV was excommunicated by the seventh pope of this name. A \"Great\" Pope of this name led the effort to convert the Saxons and names a popular type of chant. For the point, give this name held by a pope whose namesake calendar replaced the Julian one.", "answer": "<b><u>Gregory</u></b> (accept Pope <b><u>Gregory</u></b> the Great; accept Pope <b><u>Gregory</u></b> I; accept Pope <b><u>Gregory</u></b> XIII; accept Pope <b><u>Gregory</u></b> IX; accept <b><u>Gregory</u></b> Palamas; accept <b><u>Gregory</u></b> of Nazianzus; accept <b><u>Gregory</u></b> of Nyssa)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s administration fell victim to the Benalla Scandal after the title staff member dressed up as a police officer and beat up May Day protestors. This world leader has planned to curb the growth of the Calais [[kah-LAY]] Jungle and build more adequate refugee camps. After a run-off election, this politician won in a landslide victory over right-wing politician Marine le Pen [[mah-REEN luh PAHN]]. For the point, name this youngest French president in history, the successor of Fran\u00e7ois Hollande [[frahn-SWAHS oh-LAHND]].", "answer": "Emmanuel <b><u>Macron</u></b> [[mah-KROHN]] (or Emmanuel Jean-Michel Fr\u00e9d\u00e9ric <b><u>Macron</u></b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "During this event, James McCord admitted that the wife of Attorney General John N. Mitchell was essentially kidnapped due to her knowledge of it. The White House Plumbers attempted to suppress knowledge about this event outside presidential confidantes, and G. Gordon Liddy directed the five men who perpetrated it. For the point, name this illegal act done by the Committee to Re-Elect the President, or CREEP, the wiretapping of a hotel done to assist Nixon's Presidential campaign of 1972.", "answer": "<b><u>Break-In</u></b> at the <b><u>Watergate</u></b> Hotel (accept equivalents to the word \"Break-in\" like \"Burglary\"; accept \"Wiretapping\" as an equivalent to \"Break-In\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This city became a major center of <em>Rangaku</em> [[rahn-GAH-koo]] following exposure to trade with the Netherlands. Omura Sumitada granted permission for this city to be a port for Portuguese ships. This city was home to the trading post of Dejima [[deh-JEE-mah]], the only port in which foreigners could trade during the Edo Period. Because of its importance in heavy industry, this city was targeted by the plane <em>Bockscar</em> during World War Two. For the point, name this Japanese city that suffered the second, and thus far last, atomic bomb attack in history.", "answer": "<b><u>Nagasaki</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}], "bonuses": []}